Gustav Davidson Papers MS038
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Books and Ephemera, 1613 -- 1986; MS038.002; 15.6 Linear Feet
  - Gogarty, Oliver St. John: It Isn't This Time of Year at All, 1954; MS038.002.008.00026 (Box 8)
    Signature: Oliver St. John Gogarty and Gustav Davison; Tear to corner of DJ; Clippings removed from front cover and rehoused in envelope; In bag with Intimations and Collected Poems
  - Gogarty, Oliver St. John: It Isn't This Time of Year at All [Ephemera], 1954; MS038.002.008.00027 (Box 8)
    Clippings removed from book
  - Gogarty, Oliver St. John: James Augustine Joyce, 1949; MS038.002.008.00028 (Box 8)
    Signature: Oliver St. John Gogarty; The Times Herald; Cover is discolored; First printed in the Book News of the Times Herald of Dallas April 3, 1949; In bag with The Fire's Center, Birthday Poems, Thirst of the Antelope, My Last Seventy Years, An Interrupted Courtship and Echoes of Childhood; 1050 printed
    Gogarty, Oliver St. John; Joyce, James
  - Gogarty, Oliver St. John: The Collected Poems of Oliver St. John Gogarty, 1954; MS038.002.008.00029 (Box 8)
    Dedication: To Mollie Davidson from Oliver St. J. Gogarty with appreciation and affection April 23rd 1957 (inscribed 200 E 36 St after dinner); Devin-Adair Company; DJ removed to envelope; Clipping at page 98; In bag with It Isn't This Time of Year at All and Intimations
    Poems; Gogarty, Oliver St. John
  - Gogarty, Oliver St. John: The Collected Poems of Oliver St. John Gogarty [Ephemera], 1954; MS038.002.008.00030 (Box 8)
    Dust jacket of book
  - Gogarty, Oliver St. John: Perennial, 1944; MS038.002.008.00031 (Box 8)
    Signature: Oliver St. John Gogarty; Contemporary Poetry Press; DJ is completely broken and placed inside back cover; In bag with Poems of Five Decades, Enjoyment of Living, and Lot's Wife
  - Goldsmith, Elisabeth: Ancient Pagan Symbols, 1929; MS038.002.008.00032 (Box 8)
    Dedication: To Leonora Speyer with admiration Elisabeth Goldsmith March 13, 1929 Advance copy from her library Mar.19 1956 [Title page illustration number corrected]; G.P. Putnam Publishing; DJ is homemade and not original to book, frontpiece plate detached; In bag with A Garland of Elizabethan Sonnets, Naked Heel and Slow Wall
    Speyer, Leonora
  - Grene, David and Lattimore Richmond, eds.: Euripides II, 1956; MS038.002.008.00033 (Box 8)
    Dedication: For Gustav Davidson in hopes that Iphiperia takes a cruise with us, guided by Pallas Athena Yours Witter Bynner; University of Chicago Press; DJ is dirty, clippings removed to envelope; in bag with Journey with Genius and Take Away the Darkness
    Bynner, Witter
  - Grene, David and Lattimore Richmond, eds.: Euripides II [Ephemera], 1956; MS038.002.008.00034 (Box 8)
    Clippings and ephemera removed from book
  - Hanson, Phyllis ed.: Other Men's Minds The Critical Writings of Jay Lewis, 1948; MS038.002.009.00001 (Box 9)
    Signature: Phyllis Hanson; G.P. Putnam and Sons; Wear to DJ and discoloration of first leaf, price clipped
  - Hay, Sara Henderson: Field of Honor, 1933; MS038.002.009.00002 (Box 9)
    Dedication:It is a rather happy thing, to be acquainted with one's ego; to possess a certain esoteric privacy, an unassailable exclusiveness. Inestimable privilege, to find the quiet friend of one's congenial mind! For Walter Adams -- with all good wishes -- from Sara Henderson Hay March 12, 1938; The Kaleidograph Press; Good condition with some wear and discoloration to DJ; "This collectionof poems was chosen from 207 entries in the Kaleidograph book publication contest in 1933"; In bag with The Stone and the Shell; 3rd edition
  - Hay, Sara Henderson: The Stone and the Shell, 1959; MS038.002.009.00003 (Box 9)
    Dedication: For Gustav Davidson with all good wishes to him and to his Muse from Sara Henderson Hay Pittsburgh May 11 1959; University of Pittsburg Press; Minor wear to DJ; In bag with Field of Honor; 1st edition
  - Heine, Heinrich and Joseph Auslander, trans.: Bittersweet Poems, 1956; MS038.002.009.00004 (Box 9)
    Dedication: For Gus and Mollie this labor of love with all my heart Joe; Peter Pauper Press; Very good condition; In bag with Sunrise Trumpets, Marpessa, A Ballade upon a Wedding and Letters to Women
  - Hemingway, Leicester: My Brother, Ernest Hemingway, 1962; MS038.002.009.00005 (Box 9)
    World Pub; Very minor wear to DJ; 1st edition
    Hemingway, Ernest
  - Henry, Teuira: Ancient Tahiti, 1928; MS038.002.009.00006 (Box 9)
    Signature: Gustav Davidson Tahiti; Museum of Honolulu Hawaii Press; Signatures breaking apart completely, both covers detached, pages detaching; Waldoff Astoria napkin in textblock
  - Henry, Teuira: Ancient Tahiti [Ephemera], 1928; MS038.002.009.00007 (Box 9)
    Envelope book was originally housed in.
  - Hillyer, Robert: Poems for Music, 1947; MS038.002.009.00008 (Box 9)
    A.A. Knopf Publishing; Discoloration of cloth and red sticker on front cover; In bag with The Five Books of Youth; 1st Edition
  - Hillyer, Robert: The Five Books of Youth, 1920; MS038.002.009.00009 (Box 9)
    Brentano's Press; Paper on spine is missing; In bag with Poems for Music
  - How, Louis: The Other Don Juan, 1932; MS038.002.009.00010 (Box 9)
    Signature: Gustav Davidson; Harbor Press; Wear to cover edges
  - Johnson, Geoffrey: The Heart of Things, 1952; MS038.002.009.00011 (Box 9)
    Signature: Geoffrey Johnson; Williams and Norgate; Discoloration to DJ; In bag with The Ninth Wave
  - Johnson, Geoffrey: The Ninth Wave, 1948; MS038.002.009.00012 (Box 9)
    With best wishes to Gustav Davidson from Geoffrey Johnson March 31 1949; G. Harrap Publishing; DJ breaking at spine; In bag with The Heart of Things
  - Joyce, James: Ulysses, 1925; MS038.002.009.00013 (Box 9)
    Shakespeare and Company; Signatures breaking apart completely, back cover gone, pages detaching
    Joyce, James
  - Joyce, James: Ulysses [Ephemera], 1925; MS038.002.009.00014 (Box 9)
  - Keats, John and Henry John Newbold: John Keats, MS038.002.009.00015 (Box 9)
    Dedication: For the hynie and Gustav, With appreciation -- Phyllis March 30th, 1948; Thomas Nelson Press; Very poor condition, front and back cover detached and fraying greatly around edges, text block is in good condition. No Date Available
  - Kendall, James: Michael Faraday Man of Simplicity, 1955; MS038.002.009.00016 (Box 9)
    Dedication: With the author's compliments James Kendall April 1955; Faber and Faber; Minor wear to DJ, poor opening of bottom of textblock
  - Kendall, James: Young Chemists and Great Discoveries, 1939; MS038.002.009.00017 (Box 9)
    Dedication: With the author's compliments James Kendall October 1950; G. Bell and Sons Publishing; DJ very torn, some pages suffering from severe acid migration
  - Kock, Charles-Paul de: The Masterpieces of Charles-Paul de Kock: Vol V, 1903; MS038.002.009.00018 (Box 9)
    George Barrie and Son Publishing; Textblock detached from cover, pages starting to detach; Number 984 of 1000 private printing
  - Kock, Charles-Paul de: The Masterpieces of Charles-Paul de Kock: Vol VI, 1903; MS038.002.009.00019 (Box 9)
  - Laughlin, James: The Fourth Eclogue of Virgil, 1947; MS038.002.010.00001 (Box 10)
    Carroll Coleman Publisher; Folio; Privately printed for the friends of Genevieve and Carroll Coleman at Christmas nineteen hundred forty-seven; Discoloration on edges of paper
  - Lawrence, D.H.: Lady Chatterly's Lover, 1933; MS038.002.010.00002 (Box 10)
    Signature: Gustav Davidson Paris 1933; Odyssey Press; Original paper cover with a second paper cover glued to the spine, wrapped in paper-backed cloth and in a broken slipcase; 2nd Impression
    Lawrence, D. H.
  - Lawrence, D.H. and Harry T. Moore, ed.: Sex, Literature and Censorship, 1955; MS038.002.010.00003 (Box 10)
    Dedication: To Mollie Davidson with all good wishes Harry T. Moore Wellesley Hills, Mass. Oct. 30, 1955; Heineman Press; DJ is very torn and discolored, some discoloration of text block; Paperclip attached to front cover removed although slight rust mark and indentation remains
  - Le Clercq, Jacques trans.; Love Poems from the Greek Anthology, 1955; MS038.002.010.00004 (Box 10)
    Dedication: To Gustav and Mollie in affectionate remembrance -- Jacques November 1955; Peter Pauper Press; Good condition with minor wear and fading on slipcase and spine of book
  - Leach, Henry Goddard: An Interrupted Courtship, 1963; MS038.002.010.00005 (Box 10)
    Dedication: To Gustav Davidson, Great American poet and my beloved friend, my [first, the] of 1963! My [record] will be limited to 12 hours instead of 12 years. Henry Leach New York April 18 1963; Exposition Press; Christmas card in front cover; Originally in bag with The Fire's Center, Birthday Poems, James Augustine Joyce, Thirst of the Antelope, My Last Seventy Years and Echoes of Childhood
  - Leach, Henry Goddard: Echoes of Childhood, 1966; MS038.002.010.00006 (Box 10)
    Branden Press; DJ is discolored, especially on spine; Correspondence removed to envelope; Foreword by Gustav Davidson; Originally in bag with The Fire's Center, Birthday Poems, James Augustine Joyce, Thirst of the Antelope, My Last Seventy Years and An Interrupted Courtship
  - Leach, Henry Goddard: Echoes of Childhood [Ephemera], 1966; MS038.002.010.00007 (Box 10)
  - Leach, Henry Goddard: My Last Seventy Years, 1956; MS038.002.010.00008 (Box 10)
    Dedication: For Gustav Davidson poet and friend of poets from Henry Leach; Bookman Press; Good condition; Christmas card in cover; Originally in bag with The Fire's Center, Birthday Poems, James Augustine Joyce, Thirst of the Antelope, An Interrupted Courtship and Echoes of Childhood
  - Learch, Henry Goddard: The Fire's Center, 1950; MS038.002.010.00009 (Box 10)
    Dedication: To Gustav in love and admiration from Henry VIII.16-50; Fine Editions Press; DJ is discolored, especially on spine; Clippings removed to envelope; Originally in bag with Echoes of Childhood, Birthday Poems, James Augustine Joyce, Thirst of the Antelope, My Last Seventy Years and An Interrupted Courtship
  - Leach, Henry Goddard: The Fire's Center [Ephemera], 1950; MS038.002.010.00010 (Box 10)
  - Leach, Henry Goddard and Annis Goddard Young: Birthday Poems for Henry Goddard Leach from his Daughter Annis Presented on his Eightieth Birthday July 3, 1960, MS038.002.010.00011 (Box 10)
    Upper right corner bent and discoloration to cover; Correspondence and bibliographic card inside front cover; Originally in bag with The Fire's Center, James Augustine Joyce, Thrist of the Antelope, My Last Seventy Years, An Interrupted Courtship and Echoes of Childhood
  - Lear, Edward: Teapots and Quail and Other New Nonsenses, 1953; MS038.002.010.00012 (Box 10)
    Harvard University Press; DJ is torn; Preface by Angus Davidson; 1st Edition
  - LeGallienne, Richard; The Cry of the Little People, 1941; MS038.002.010.00013 (Box 10)
    Signature of LeGallienne; Sixty-fifth Street Bookshop; Wear at fold; Originally in bag with Richard Le Gallienne: A Centenary Memoir-Anthology
  - Lengyel, Cornel: El Dorado Forest, 1986; MS038.002.010.00014 (Box 10)
    Dedication: For Mollie Davidson -- With affectionate greetings (and in fond remembrance of Gustav) as ever Cornel Lengyel New Years 1987; Hillside Press; In mailing envelope; Originally in bag with The Master Plan, Four Dozen Songs, and DJ for The Lookout's Letter
  - Lengyel, Cornel; Four Dozen Songs, 1973; MS038.002.010.00015 (Box 10)
    Dedication: For Mollie once again warm greetings Cornel Lengyel 4/30/73; Dragon's Teeth Press; Also contains musical scores; Originally in bag with The Master Plan, Four Dozen Songs, and DJ for The Lookout's Letter; Revised Edition
  - Lengyel, Cornell: The Lookout's Letter [Dustjacket], 1971; MS038.002.010.00016 (Box 10)
    Dragon's Teeth Press; DJ only; Originally in bag with The Master Plan, Four Dozen Songs, and El Dorado Forest
  - Lengyel, Cornel, 1978; MS038.002.010.00017 (Box 10)
    Dedication: For Molly Davidson with all good wishes Cornell Lengyel New Year 1979; Dragon's Teeth Press; Originally in bag with Four Dozen Songs, DJ for The Lookout's letter, and El Dorado Forest; 1st edition limited
  - Leonard Parson Limited: A Garland of Elizabethan Sonnets, 1923; MS038.002.010.00018 (Box 10)
    Dedication: With Gustav with affection Leonora 1951; minor wear to cover, clipping in front cover with minor acid burning inside cover (wrapped in tissue); Originally in bag with Ancient Pagan Symbols, Naked Heel and Slow Wall; 402 of 500 copies
  - Leonard, William Ellery trans.: Beowulf, 1932; MS038.002.010.00019 (Box 10)
    Signature: Gustav Davidson 1932; Random House; Last signature pulling out of binding, wear to headbands and edges of cover, multi-colored ink; 950 copies "this being number Review"
  - Lewis, Joseph: The Ten Commandments, 1946; MS038.002.010.00020 (Box 10)
    Signature: Joseph Lewis; Freethought Press Association; Discoloration to spine and breaking of cloth at hinges
  - Lord, Gigi: Toppling After Itself, 1969; MS038.002.010.00021 (Box 10)
    Dedication: November 1969 To Gustav Davidson With all good wishes... Best, Gigi Lord; South and West Inc. Publishers; Good condition; First place award in the National Federation of State Poetry Socities Contest for 1968
  - Louys, Pierre: The Collected Works of Pierre Louys, 1932; MS038.002.010.00022 (Box 10)
    Liveright Press; DJ does not appear to be original -- torn and faded yellow paper; binding is loose and front hinge is breaking
  - Louys, Pierre: Woman and Puppet, 1927; MS038.002.010.00023 (Box 10)
    Pierre Louys Society; Good condition; Scrap paper with notes inside textblock; Limited run of 1250 with 990 for America, copy not numbered
  - Luhan, Mabel Dodge: Lorenzo in Taos, 1932; MS038.002.010.00024 (Box 10)
    Knopf Publishing; Signatures completely separating and large number of pages missing, 244 of 352 pages present; 1st edition travel memoir about D. H. Lawrence
  - Lynen, John F.: The Pastorial Art of Robert Frost, 1960; MS038.002.010.00025 (Box 10)
    Yale University Press; Good condition; Correspondence and clippings in back cover; Originally in bag with In the Clearing and A Masque of Mercy
  - Macdougaall, Allan Ross, ed.: The Letters of Edna St. Vincent Millay, 1952; MS038.002.010.00026 (Box 10)
    Signature: Gustav Davidson; Harper and Brothers Publishing; Minor wear to DJ; 1st edition
  - Markham, Edwin: The Star of Araby, 1937; MS038.002.010.00027 (Box 10)
    Dedication: Your friend, Edwin Markham. Staten Island, N.Y.; John Willig Press; DJ is glassine with a spider web design which is cracked and detached, discoloration of cover; With note card with bibliographic info and note from title page "First published in honor of the poet's eighty-fifth birthday April 23, 1937"
  - Masters, Hardin W.: Edgar Lee Masters A Centenary Memoir-Anthology, 1972; MS038.002.010.00028 (Box 10)
    A.S. Barnes Publishing; Minor tears to DJ; Printed for PSA; 1st edition; another copy located in subject files
  - McCarthy, James Remington: A Matter of Time The Story of the Watch, 1947; MS038.002.010.00029 (Box 10)
    Dedication: Dear Gus (Meaning of course Gus Davidson) I don't know what time is -- do you? Is it the ticking of a clock? Or is it the passing of thought beautiful or otherwise? Best - Jim (James Remington McCarthy August 4, 1950); Harper and Brothers Publishing; DJ is completely fallen apart and removed to envelope; Damage to lower front corner of cover
  - McCarthy, James Remington: A Matter of Time The Story of the Watch [Ephemera], 1947; MS038.002.010.00030 (Box 10)
    Dustjacket of book
  - McCarthy, James Remington: Rings through the Ages An Informal History, 1945; MS038.002.010.00031 (Box 10)
    Dedication: To Gus Davidson Look for no poetry here, my friend but look for beautiful baloney Best Jim (James Remington McCarthy) August 4, 1950; Harper Publishing; Very good condition; 1st edition
  - McNeill, Warren Albert: Caballian Harmonics, 1928; MS038.002.011.00001 (Box 11)
    Dedication: To our dear friend Gustav Davidson from Esther and Richard Ellis We printed this book, while you were in the far off "ctristrals(?)", and it is now presented you upon your first visit to The Georgian Press in Westport, CT since you return to this country September 21st 1929; Random House; Front and back covers detached, powdery flaking of leather, discolored pages; a special edition of 18 of which this is 12 -- signed by Richard W. Ellis
  - Menese, Enrique: Una Novela Que Empieza Por el Fin, 1927; MS038.002.011.00002 (Box 11)
    Spanish dedication signed by Enrique Meneses 21/8/33; Martin Y. Mena Publisher; Spine covering is completely worn away and stitching is exposed; Originally in bag separately; Letter indicated that Menese and Davidson cooperated on production
  - Merejkevski, Dmitri and Bernard Guilbert Guerney: The Menace of the Mob, 1921; MS038.002.011.00003 (Box 11)
    Dedication in Russian from Bernard Guilbert Buerney to Gustav Davidson January 18, 1941; Nicholas L. Brown Publisher; Good condition
  - Meyerson, Edward L.: Liturgy for the Living, Selected Poems 1960-1975, 1976; MS038.002.011.00004 (Box 11)
    Dedication: December 1976 For Mollie, With fond recollections; and memorable occasions with you and Gustav clearly recalled. Good health and cheer for the New Year... And many satisfactions... Ed and Alice; Golden Quill Press; Very good condition
  - Meyerson, Edward L. ed.: San Carlos Poetry Workshop Anthology, 1974; MS038.002.011.00005 (Box 11)
    Dedication: 3/27/75 For Mollie Davidson, With good wishes and affection, Ed. Alice Philip; San Carlos Fine Arts Commission; Very good condition
  - Meyerson, Edward L. ed.: San Carlos Poetry Workshop Anthology, 1974; MS038.002.011.00006 (Box 11)
    Dedication: 3/12/75 For Mollie Davidson -- With friendship and fond memories of Gustav. Ed Meyerson; San Carlos Fine Arts Commission; Very good condition
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent: A Few Figs From Thistles, 1920; MS038.002.011.00007 (Box 11)
    Frank Shay Publisher; Extremely poor condition, cover completely broken and detached, pages fragile and breaking out of textblock; Originally in bag with The King's Henchmen, Mine the Harvest and Fatal Interview
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent: Collected Sonnets, 1941; MS038.002.011.00008 (Box 11)
    Harper and Brothers Publishing; In slipcase that is worn, book itself has only minor wear, cloth bookmark; 1st edition
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent: Fatal Interview, 1931; MS038.002.011.00009 (Box 11)
    Signature: Marguerite Jauvrin Adams; Harper and Brothers Publishing; Very poor condition, front cover almost detached, extreme wear to edges of cover; Originally in bag with The King's Henchmen, Mine the Harvest and A Few Figs; 16th Printing
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent: Mine the Harvest, 1954; MS038.002.011.00010 (Box 11)
    Dedication: Leonora Speyer I choose a few short ones (all lovelies!) [with checkmarks in table of contents indicating selections]; Harper and Brothers Publishing; Tearing to DJ, acid discoloration to title page; Originally in bag with The King's Henchmen, Fatal Interview and A Few Figs; 1st edition
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent: The King's Henchmen, 1927; MS038.002.011.00011 (Box 11)
    Harper and Brothers Publishers; Good condition; Bibliographic card in front cover; Originally In bag with Mine the Harvest, Fatal Interview and A Few Figs; 1st edition
  - Moore, Marianne: Nevertheless, 1944; MS038.002.011.00012 (Box 11)
    Macmillian Press; DJ is priceclipped and worn; Review copy notice in front cover; Originally in bag with Tell Me, Tell Me and Puss in Boots; 1st printing
  - Moore, Marianne: Puss in Boots, The Sleeping Beauty and Cinderella, 1963; MS038.002.011.00013 (Box 11)
    Dedication: For Mollie Davidson my gratitude for many reasons; for a visit and miniature colie and avocado tree Forgiving me so much! Marianne Moore April 24, 1967; Macmillian Press; DJ is worn and discolored; Correspondence and clippings moved to envelope; Originally in bag with Nevertheless and Tell Me Tell Me
  - Moore, Marianne: Puss in Boots, The Sleeping Beauty and Cinderella [Ephemera], 1963; MS038.002.011.00014 (Box 11)
    Correspondence and clipping removed from book
  - Moore, Marianne: Tell Me Tell Me, 1967; MS038.002.011.00015 (Box 11)
    Dedication: Dear angel friends, Mollie and Gustav Davidson, You gave me not only an angel but somethng I need: the sinfificance of an an angel "messenger" and always shall I have him near me strong and sharp. Doves, priously, books, and a visit that lives in the mind of the hermit (?) of Marianne of 35 West Ninth Street April 21, 1967; Viking Press; Good condition; Originally in bag with Tell me Tell me and Puss in Boots
  - Moore, Thomas: The Loves of the Angels, 1823; MS038.002.011.00016 (Box 11)
    Longman, Hurst, Rees, Orme, and Brown Publishers; Poor condition, wrapped in cardboard with a cardstock label, board detaching and spine very worn, foxing of papers; 2nd edition
  - Morley, Christopher: A Letter to Leonora, MS038.002.011.00017 (Box 11)
    Signature: Christopher Morley; Marshal Field publisher; Discoloration and wear to cover; Number 43 of 125. No Date Available
  - Mosher, Thomas B. ed.: Bibelot: Volume V Testimonial Edition, 1899; MS038.002.011.00018 (Box 11)
    Thomas B. Mosher Publisher; Binding separating from textblock, textblock cracking, title glued to outer spine
  - Moult, Thomas: The Best Poems of 1931, MS038.002.011.00019 (Box 11)
    Dedication: For Marguerite- In the fellowship of song Leslie; Jonathan Cape, Limited Publisher; Wear to DJ
  - Nabokov, Vladimar ed.: Three Russian Poets, Selections from Pushkin, Lermontov, and Tyutchev in new translations, 1944; MS038.002.011.00020 (Box 11)
    New Directions Publishing; Wear and discoloration on spine/fold
  - Nelson, Harry W.: Not of This Star Dust, 1973; MS038.002.011.00021 (Box 11)
    Blue Leaf Editions; Good condition; In envelope with The Winter Tree; Pamplet and label interleaved in book
  - Nelson, Harry W.: The Winter Tree, 1972; MS038.002.011.00022 (Box 11)
    Blue Leaf Editions; In envelope with Not of this Star Dust; Letter inside front cover removed to envelope
  - Nelson, Harry W: The Winter Tree [Ephemera], 1972; MS038.002.011.00023 (Box 11)
    Correspondence from book
  - Nelson, Harry W.: The Winter Tree, 1972; MS038.002.011.00024 (Box 11)
    Dedication: With deepest appreciation Harry W. Nelson; Blue Leaf Editions; Very slight discoloration of front cover; Tri-fold promotional flyer for book in back cover; 1st edition
  - Newcomb, Thomas: A New Collection of Original Epigrams, and Minor Odes, 1762; MS038.002.011.00025 (Box 11)
    Dedication: from Charence Derwent to Gustav Davidson May 6, 1955; H. Serjeant Publisher; Possibly rebound; Minor wear to spine; Additional calligraphy on back pages
  - Nicholl, Louise Townsend: Life is the Flesh, 1947; MS038.002.011.00026 (Box 11)
    E.P. Dutton Publisher; Minor wear to DJ; 1st Edition; limited to 400 copies
  - Nordic, Rolla K.: The Tarot shows the Path, 1960; MS038.002.011.00027 (Box 11)
    Dedication: To Gustav Davidson with grateful thanks and blessings Rolla Nordic; Regency Press; Wear and discoloration to DJ
  - Norris, Gordon W.: Pagan Road, 1956; MS038.002.011.00028 (Box 11)
    Dedication: For Gustav Davison, with best wishes, Gordon W. Norris October 23, 1956; Hesperia House Press; Discoloration and torn edges of DJ
  - Oakeshott, Walter ed.: The Douce Apocalypse with an introduction and notes by A.G. and W.O. Hassall, 1961; MS038.002.011.00029 (Box 11)
    Notations on page 5; ThomasYoseloff Publisher; DJ is torn; Letter inside front cover; See also Steuben Glass and the "Poetry in Crystal" Exhibit
  - Ogburn, Dorothy and Charlton: The Renaissance Man of England, 1955; MS038.002.011.00030 (Box 11)